Tip number 5: Collecting Jewelry Over Time.
Instead of going out on one grand buying trip, as much fun as that may be, it's a better and more accurate reflection of your personality if you slowly collect key pieces of jewelry over time.
For example, do a single initial buying trip and find out what you need.
Then, after that, continue to buy pieces when you go shopping in the future.
For example, if someone gives you a gift certificate for your birthday, this is a great opportunity to buy that ring that you've been eying for the past couple months.
It's also a great way to fill in holes in your jewelry wardrobe without a great outlay of money all at one time.
Most people's budget cannot afford to spend an enormous amount of money all at one time on jewelry or anything else.
Therefore it's a more practical solution to spread out your jewelry acquisition over a period of time.
Even your whole lifetime.
The exception to this rule is costume jewelry.
If you like costume jewelry and you want to just buy a big bunch of it all at once it's very easy to do this within a limited budget at either an antiques fair or a knock off place or a discount store like Target or Mervyns.
Both of these places have really cute costume jewelry, and you can go spend a lot of money, all lot at once, and completely change your jewelry wardrobe.